

# CHARLOTTA SÖDERHOLM

PROFESSIONAL MULTITASKER

# **PROFILE**

Years in customer service has taught me a lot about providing customer oriented service. I'm at my best when I can utilize my problem solving skills and be of help to others. I create a functioning workspace around me. I am proactive and a solution minded thinker.

## SKILLS

### Languages

Swedish (native), Finnish and English, Professional proficiency

#### Systems and programs

Office Word, Excel; Micros Oracle; MaraPlan; ResDiary; HotelLinx; Restolution; Lounastaja; Business Suite; Google My Business; InBliss: Avarn; Smartum; Edenred; E-passi; Eazybreak

## EDUCATIONAL TRAINING

### **Turku University of Applied Sciences**

**Bachelor of Hospitality Management** 

- · Graduated in 2007
- Production and Management of Services
- Facility Management
- · Usability of workspace
- Strategic Facilities Management

#### HOW TO REACH ME

Mobile: 0405318180

Email: charlotta.soderholm@pp.inet.fi

Address: Kalevankatu 46 A 10, 00180 Helsinki www.linkedin.com/in/charlottasoderholm/

## CHARACTER REFERENCES

### Sanni Vikman

Education specialist University of Helsinki sanni.vikman@helsinki.fi

#### Aino Pihlava

Global Management Trainee ISS Palvelut pihlavaaino@gmail.com

### Aila Bonifacio

Head Waitress Hotel Kämp aila.bonifacio@hotelkamp.com

# COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

# MLL Ruoholahti-Jätkäsaari local organisation

Member of the Board 2021

Member and Volunteer 2018

- Organising happenings for children wih the aim to bring local families together
- Working proactively to help families by provding information for help facilitated by the main organisation

# CHARLOTTA SÖDERHOLM

CAREER SUMMARY

# Head Waitress 05/2008- present Barona henkilöstöpalvelut

I start working with Opteam and Staff+, later Barona, in 2008 when I move to Helsinki. Later the agency waitressing stops and turns into full time employment, until, due to recent global events, I am laid off from my dayjob. Thanks to my experience I get shifts as Head Waitress at my old workplace, Hotel Kämp. There I enjoy the confidence of my supervisors despite not being directly employed, to once again engage in the reporting and operate as Manager on Duty.

Keywords: Adaptability, Number Accuracy, Problem solving skills, Working under Pressure

# Manager on Duty 01/2020-05/2021 Makkis ja Pekkis Oy

I am part of the team opening the first of many-to-be BAD Restaurants. We refine the concept and create operating models for the upcoming restaurants. Later I operate the unit on my own reporting to the Restaurant Manager. My work includes customer service, reporting and maintaining a positive ambiance. In a busy environment it is important to work proactively and prioritise. My ability to work independently and self-direkt as well as my happy service attitude are highlighted qualities here. We work closely together with Lounastaja, a startup company that produces online publishing services, where I provide user experience consultation.

Keywords: Working Independently, Proactivity, Ability to Multitask, Developing Work Methods

# Head Waitress 07/2016-01/2020 Kämp Oy

Hotel Kämp is a five star hotel and the only one in Finland to be a member of the Leading Hotels of the World. LHW-membership requires following certain standards very closely. My responsibilities lie within operating as Team Lead for the Breakfast Team together with three others, reporting to the Restaurant Manager.

As Head Waitress my work includes supporting staff, ensuring customer satisfaction and greeting guests. The work requires a lot of contact with third party service providers, such as Maintenance, IT, Finance and Housekeeping. As HR department does not exist, the onboarding process, questions about the Collective Agreement and solving internal disputes are an essential part of our responsibilities.

I create an onboarding procedure plan for our unit. Together we create new operating models and develop the service process. I am part of a team that does reporting and controlling of all F&B depatments' sales reports, before sending the data to Finance. For a long time I have the sole responsibility for it. This teaches me number accuracy and gives me a deeper understanding of the department's financial background.

Keywords: Interpersonal Skills, High Profile Guests, Multicultural Work Community, Improving Work Methods, Number Accuracy,

## Restaurant Manager 04/2015-08/2016 EF-Restaurants

I am part of the team opening a new restaurant, in the role of consulting the owners in operational matters. I do the base work for the POS- system as well as the tools for tracking work hours according to the Collective Agreement. I am later injured and unable to continue working here

Keywords: Problem Solving Skills, Implementing skills, Excel

# Event Coordinator 04/2012-04/2015 Palace Kämp Ravintolat Oy/Royal Ravintolat Oy

Tapahtumatalo Bank provided a venue, meeting rooms and services as well as buffet lunch on a daily bases. I am working in all departments as Shift Manager, also being responsible for Inventory Management, Reporting and Controlling of sales before sending data to Finance

Keywords: Event planning, Catering, Number Accuracy, Time Management